<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
 This is a WordPress eXtended RSS file generated by WordPress as an export of your site.
 It contains information about your site's posts, pages, comments, categories, and other content.
 You may use this file to transfer that content from one site to another.
 This file is not intended to serve as a complete backup of your site.

 To import this information into a WordPress site follow these steps:
 1. Log in to that site as an administrator.
 2. Go to Tools: Import in the WordPress admin panel.
 3. Install the "WordPress" importer from the list.
 4. Activate & Run Importer.
 5. Upload this file using the form provided on that page.
 6. You will first be asked to map the authors in this export file to users
    on the site. For each author, you may choose to map to an
    existing user on the site or to create a new user.
 7. WordPress will then import each of the posts, pages, comments, categories, etc.
    contained in this file into your site.
-->
<!-- generator="WordPress.com" created="2021-12-21 17:00"-->
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:excerpt="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/excerpt/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:wp="http://wordpress.org/export/1.2/">
  <channel>
<title>The School of Tunah</title>
<link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog</link>
<description>~a collection of my thoughts and experiences in education~</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 17:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
<language>en</language>
<wp:wxr_version>1.2</wp:wxr_version>
<wp:base_site_url>http://wordpress.com/</wp:base_site_url>
<wp:base_blog_url>http://thepassionpost.home.blog</wp:base_blog_url>
<wp:author>
  <wp:author_id>145138234</wp:author_id>
  <wp:author_login>tinahhong</wp:author_login>
  <wp:author_email>tinahhong@outlook.com</wp:author_email>
  <wp:author_display_name><![CDATA[Tinah Hong]]></wp:author_display_name>
  <wp:author_first_name><![CDATA[Tinah]]></wp:author_first_name>
  <wp:author_last_name><![CDATA[Hong]]></wp:author_last_name>
</wp:author>
<wp:category>
  <wp:term_id>1</wp:term_id>
  <wp:category_nicename>uncategorized</wp:category_nicename>
  <wp:category_parent/>
  <wp:cat_name><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></wp:cat_name>
</wp:category>
<wp:term>
  <wp:term_id>1357</wp:term_id>
  <wp:term_taxonomy>nav_menu</wp:term_taxonomy>
  <wp:term_slug>primary</wp:term_slug>
  <wp:term_name><![CDATA[Primary]]></wp:term_name>
</wp:term>
<generator>http://wordpress.com/</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://thepassionposthome.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/cropped-mountain1.jpg?w=32</url>
	<title>The School of Tunah</title>
	<link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 

<item>
  <title>The Concept of Race</title>
  <link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog/2018/10/06/the-concept-of-race/</link>
  <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 04:47:40 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>tinahhong</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepassionpost.home.blog/?p=9</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[How many races are there? Today, there are almost an undefined number of races: Caucasian, Asian, Hispanic, Latino, Native American, etc. Our idea of race is dynamic, as our definition of it has expanded and evolved over time. Today, we use race in such a way that it has become a significant part of our identity, and many never learn that race is a social construct. In fact, contrary to what many people believe, there is no scientific basis of race.

A few centuries ago, renown American scientist, Samuel Morton, claimed that there were only 5 major races: "Caucasians," "Mongolians," "Southeast Asians," "Native Americans," and "Blacks," but where did these classifications originate from?

It turns out, the concept of race was invented by Morton in the early nineteenth century. Known as the father of scientific racism, he collected skulls and filled the brain cavities with lead. For him, the differing volumes and shapes were evidence of the intellectual superiority of the "Caucasians;" similarly, his "craniology" led him to claim that blacks, or "Ethiopians," were the least intelligent of the races. Morton claimed that each race was a separate act of creation, and that "Caucasians" were created as the ideal race. This conclusion led to the adoption of the concept of race by the defenders of slavery in North America. Essentially, they used it to claim an inherent inferiority of blacks that would justify their subhuman treatment of slaves.

After Morton's death in 1851, the <i>Charleston Medical Journal</i> praised him for “giving to the negro his true position as an inferior race.”

Later, an Austrian physician named Franz Joseph Gall invented the study of Phrenology, a science that linked the morphology of the brain to the character and intellect of the human. The science supported the view that the power dynamic between blacks and white slaveowners was natural and inevitable, which further solidified the inferiority of the blacks in the eyes of the white slaveowners.

Today, the majority of established scientists view phrenology as a pseudoscience. The patterns and sizes of certain bumps of a brain could give little possible indication of the moral and intellectual capabilities of a person. The idea is ludicrous, and scientific medicine and mainstream neurologists labeled it as such by the end of the nineteenth century.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="310"]<img id="image" class=" aligncenter" src="http://www.anatomybox.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/vintage-phrenology.jpg" width="310" height="395" /> <span style="display:inline !important;float:none;background-color:transparent;color:#3d596d;cursor:text;font-family:'Noto Serif', Georgia, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif;font-size:16px;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;font-weight:400;letter-spacing:normal;line-height:19.2px;orphans:2;text-align:left;text-decoration:none;text-indent:0;text-transform:none;white-space:normal;word-spacing:0;"> A diagram of the attributes associated with specific locations on the skull as described by the pseudoscience of phrenology</span>[/caption]

In fact, the whole concept of race does not have any genetic or scientific basis. The Human Genome Project has concluded that humans are 99.9% genetically identical, which undermines the belief of the superiority or inferiority of any race. Yet, today we still accept this concept of race, and we often associate skin color as the dividing barrier between groups of people. But even the differences in our appearance are merely a consequence of where our ancestors grew up. For example, those whose ancestors grew up near the equator have more melanin to protect against ultraviolet radiation, and those whose ancestors grew up near the poles tend to have lighter skin to promote vitamin D production. Yet the genes that pass down these traits are often so diverse due to migration and breeding that there are no fixed traits associated with specific geographic location.

In the end, there is only one true race: <i>Homo Sapiens, </i>the human race. This fact is widely known, yet the legacy of Samuel Morten remains obvious today. Today, race is still used to categorize people, and these categories are determined by the people in power. Additionally, the concept plays a prominent role in determining political agendas, demographics, stereotypes, and our sense of identity. Ever since Morten created scientific racism, race has been used as a barrier to divide and isolate groups of people all over the world.

One of the most extreme examples of race being used in this way was the Holocaust, the systematic slaughter of 6 million Jews. The genocide was organized by the Nazis as The Final Solution to the "Jewish Question" which had arisen during the 19th and 20th centuries. At this time, tensions rose as Europe debated over the appropriate status and treatment of Jews in society. Increasingly, there became an anti-Semitic attitude in Germany as many declared that Jews could not be assimilated into their society. Pretty soon, there was a "de-jewifying" of the press, education, culture, state, and economy. Jews were not to marry non-Jews, and mass acts of violence further pushed Jews out of German society. This culminated to a point where Hitler and the Nazis proposed The Final Solution: the extermination of Jews.

In addition to Jews, the Nazis also targeted Gypsies, Poles, Ukrainians, people with disabilities, and homosexuals, among other minorities. Central to the Nazis political ideology was the notion of racial purifying, a concept explained in <i>Mein Kampf</i>, Hitler's autobiography that he wrote while imprisoned. Within the book are expressions of Hitler's racist beliefs, which include the idea that Aryans are the "master" race, while Jews are the "parasite."

According to Hitler, an Aryan is a German with fair skin, blond hair and blue eyes; however, considering that race is a societal construct, there is no true scientific basis for determining who is of the Aryan race. In fact, Hessy Taft, whose face was plastered on posters that were propagated as the "ideal Aryan child," was in fact a Jew. Taft was selected as a poster child because of her physical qualities, but because there is so much variation between the physical appearance of people within the same race, the Nazis ironically mistook her for an Aryan. The arbitrary criteria for determining who is a member of a certain race further supports the fact that race has no genetic or biological roots.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="320"]<img class="mw-mmv-final-image jpg mw-mmv-dialog-is-open aligncenter" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/89/Hessy_Levinsons_Taft.jpg" alt="Hessy Levinsons Taft.jpg" width="320" height="447" /> <span style="display:inline !important;float:none;background-color:transparent;color:#3d596d;cursor:text;font-family:'Noto Serif', Georgia, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif;font-size:16px;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;font-weight:400;letter-spacing:normal;line-height:19.2px;orphans:2;text-align:left;text-decoration:none;text-indent:0;text-transform:none;white-space:normal;word-spacing:0;"> Hessy Taft, a Jewish baby portrayed in Nazi propaganda as a model of the perfect Aryan child</span>[/caption]

There is no consensus on any scientific evidence supporting either notion of Aryans being a superior race or of Jews being an inferior one. Yet Hitler makes countless empty claims to argue that Aryans should rule over all others. Unfortunately, the desperate state of the German people after their humiliation post-WWI allowed the rise of Hitler and his Nazi Party, and the legitimacy of his racist ideology.

Hitler used the abstract construct of race to create an overwhelming sense of identity within the German population. While those deemed part of the Aryan race rallied, the border between them and people of different ethnicities thickened. This exclusive "us vs. them" attitude is common and counterproductive. It serves primarily to justify segregation and the unequal treatment of minorities within societies. But since the concept of race was created for this purpose, it is no surprise that this attitude is so prevalent today.

The remnants of our country's xenophobia and racism is evident by the demography of certain cities. The poverty-stricken areas that we call ghettos are mostly composed of minorities that clumped together due to social and legal discrimination, and economic pressure. Because most of the residents are poor, the schools are underfunded, and since education is seen as the key to economic mobility, many of those born in the ghetto seem destined to stay there. The cycle of poverty within these areas doesn't seem like it will be broken any time soon. Furthermore, while most legal discrimination has been eradicated today, some people of color still cannot be sure that when they move into a new neighborhood they will not be discriminated against on the basis of their skin color.

Individually, any person not born of privilege can feel that their identity may be dragging them down, not only because of historical discrimination, but also because discrimination still exists today. Any minority may be harassed on the street or denied a job position because of their ethnicity. At the very least, minorities are subject to subconscious stereotypes that may have done nothing to perpetuate.

While racism is much less prevalent today than it was a few decades ago, there are still many negative stereotypes that cause people to discriminate against people of different ethnic backgrounds. Think, for example, the association of Muslims and terrorists, or the higher likelihood for a cop to shoot an unarmed black man.

Stephon Clark, Laquan McDonald, Walter Scott, are all black men whose deaths shocked the nation. Neither Stephon Clark nor Walter Scott were armed, and all of the men had their backs turned to the police when they were shot. Yet the cops that killed them claimed that they all "feared for their lives." These deaths incited national outrage, including many Black Lives Matter rallies to protest police brutality.

[caption id="" align="aligncenter" width="466"]<img class=" aligncenter" title="" src="https://assets.teenvogue.com/photos/5780286c2fd18be463501ad6/3:2/w_584/blm.jpg" alt="" width="466" height="310" /> <span style="display:inline !important;float:none;background-color:transparent;color:#3d596d;cursor:text;font-family:'Noto Serif', Georgia, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif;font-size:16px;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;font-weight:400;letter-spacing:normal;line-height:19.2px;orphans:2;text-align:left;text-decoration:none;text-indent:0;text-transform:none;white-space:normal;word-spacing:0;"> Black Lives Matter rally following the death of Alton Sterling</span>[/caption]

While there are ongoing debates on whether or not the shootings had anything to do with racial bias, cops from a 2005 study by Florida State University demonstrated racial bias in response to criminal suspects. 50 police officers were presented with photographs of men holding either a gun or a cell phone. They were forced to make split-second decisions on whether to shoot, in case the suspect had a gun, or not. The study found that the officers were more likely to mistakenly shoot unarmed black suspects. Fortunately though, this bias seemed to go away after extensive training.

This study is evidence that even people who claim that they treat everyone equally may harbor some insidious bias that they are not aware of. This is because of the complexities of our brains. Unlike any other species of animals, <em>Homo Sapiens</em> have two layers of the brain: the conscience, and the subconscious. Our consciousness is what we think controls our actions, but in reality, our subconsciousness motivates most of our actions, including the stereotyping that we have evolved to do. This process is essential in many circumstances. For example, if you were to see a bear kill a human, then you would be smart to avoid them in the future, lest they kill you. And although every individual is unique, it is essential that we don't give every single bear the benefit of the doubt. Instead, we associate the actions of a few bears with every bear. From an evolutionary standpoint, our ability to stereotype is imperative to the survival of our species. But while stereotyping bears is acceptable, humans are so complex and diverse that we cannot use the character or actions of one person as an indicator of all the people within their race, gender, religion, etc.

Because mainstream media imbues racial biases within our subconsciousness at a young age, it may be impossible to be completely free from them. But recognizing that we all have these prejudices is a good first step to begin the conscious fight to challenge them.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>9</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-10-06 04:47:40</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-10-06 04:47:40</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2018-10-07 22:12:11</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2018-10-07 22:12:11</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-concept-of-race</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1538801264]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[22889982617]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Hope for the Homeless</title>
  <link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog/2018/10/28/hope-for-the-homeless/</link>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:10:50 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>tinahhong</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepassionpost.home.blog/?p=58</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[There's nothing better than a carefree stroll down North Chicago. Grand, twisting skyscrapers loom over me as I gaze at the horizon, waving at the passengers on a cruise boat as they float down a lazy river. Suddenly, a voice calls up at me. At my feet, a man sits, rattling a cup of spare change. For a split second, his eyes lock on to mine, but my eyes promptly avert their gaze, suddenly finding the urge to check my phone's lock screen. I walk away.

<img class="  wp-image-62 aligncenter" src="https://thepassionposthome.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/10-best-places-to-visit-in-usa-chicago-illinois.jpg" alt="10-Best-places-to-visit-in-usa-Chicago-Illinois" width="480" height="319" />

This display of economic disparity is common whenever anyone walks down a busy metropolitan area. Extreme wealth and excess are prevalent in one area, and sitting at the corners and intersections are humans whose situations represent a lack of these. Sometimes, upon passing a homeless person, someone might give a sad, pitying smile. Most times, they will purposely not acknowledge the existence of the person asking them for spare change. Worse yet, people will look upon the homeless with disdain, asking questions like, <em>why don't homeless people just get jobs</em>?

Questions like these are completely valid, but when no attempt is made to find the answers, they just become a way to absolve the guilt of abandoning a person in need. This is analogous to hurling defamatory comments at a victim of sexual assault. "Well, what were you wearing?" "how much did you drink?"―victim-blaming makes one feel less uncomfortable about a situation because somehow, these questions make it seem like what happened was justified, so there's no need to extend empathy. In this way, ignorance is bliss, but this obviously problematic attitude fuels many popular misconceptions about homeless people.

In fact, there are many factors that limit a homeless person's economic mobility, starting with jobs. Simply put, there are more people than jobs, and even entry-level job positions are limited. This results in competition, and for liability issues, employers would rather hire people with stable addresses. It's also not hard to believe that most companies take into account the stigma surrounding homeless people in the hiring process. Many people believe that those who are homeless are in their situation because of laziness. However, this is false, as the estimated number of homeless people in the U.S. is 554,000 people, and of this population, the employment rate is 44%. This percentage becomes even higher when you account for how many are children, elderly, or disabled. Most homeless people make an effort to improve their situation. This is obviously difficult, as not only are jobs harder to obtain for homeless people, but this statistic of employed homeless is proof of the widening gap between wages and rents.

It is also important to realize the role that luck plays in homelessness. It is pure luck that some people are born in wealthy families. Similarly, it is bad luck that some people are born in destitute neighborhoods. In this case, I truly wonder how some people can look down at those born less fortunate than themselves.

<img class="  wp-image-63 aligncenter" src="https://thepassionposthome.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/sign.jpg" alt="sign" width="321" height="286" />

A few weeks ago, when my friends asked me to go downtown and pass out lunches to homeless people on the street, I hesitated. A common stereotype of homeless people is that they blow all their money doing drugs and drinking alcohol. If this were the case, why should I support them with food so that they can continue to indulge in these addictions?

However, I didn't have to think very hard to realize that this stereotype is not at all a fair representation of the majority of homeless people. In fact, I was excited to potentially make a difference in some people's lives. So on October 13, I stood with my friends outside Union Station, 30 packages of food and toiletries strapped to our backs. Our mission was to spread happiness to the people we would encounter, and to gain insight into homelessness. We would listen to their stories, offer them food, and pray for them.

We were taken aback by the first experience that we had. A man stood at the corner of an intersection. While taking the food that we offered, he grumbled, "why is this so squished?" We also offered him socks, which he took, saying, "These are children's socks, what am I supposed to do with these?" What really confused me was how picky and ungrateful he could be in his situation. We offered to pray for him, but he offhandedly dismissed us.

After this, we were filled with more reserve about the whole trip. But we weren't there to be seen as great, compassionate people—we were there to spread hope to the homeless. So we continued on, and we quickly saw that the first person we met was an outlier compared to the other people that we encountered.

We passed by one little kid sitting on a bucket at the corner of an intersection. He held up a sign that said, "lost my family when my house burned down 2 days ago. Please help." He looked despondent, as anyone would in his situation. It was clear that the emotions from the fire were still raw because he would not meet our eyes when he took the food and supplies that we offered.

An older man sat nearby, keeping him company. As we turned to leave, he asked us for our names. He gave us his: Tyler. We stood there, nodding at each other. As strangers, there was little more we could say in that busy intersection. But this gesture, although small, felt genuine. It felt like saying our names conveyed all of our heartfelt thoughts, like his gratitude could be read in the short silence lasting the time it took for the pedestrian light to flash.

We were told by some that we were great people, and in a moment of happiness it felt like they had gifted us back. I realized, that while the physical lunch is the greatest need for some of the homeless people that we encountered, the mere presence of people who genuinely want to extend a helping hand can be just as rewarding.

Another man just across the street had a surprising prayer request—he wanted to thank God for all that he had. My friend teared up as she delivered her prayer.

Another man sat by a street light, selling $5 calligraphy. He works hard to make his money on the streets. He is a war veteran. He has a daughter who he works to provide for. Only when we asked him about prayer requests did he mention that he had cancer. I felt so grateful to be able to provide him with some food.

<img src="https://thepassionposthome.files.wordpress.com/2018/10/drawing.jpg?w=1820" alt="drawing.jpg" width="910" height="407" />

Now, was every story that we heard truthful? Were some sob stories created to exploit us? I'll never know. But nothing productive results from doubting people's stories. And if I was able to make a positive difference in anyone's life, then the experience was worthwhile.

But the most important thing that I took away from the trip was enlightenment. Ignorance and a lack of compassion cause homelessness to be heavily stigmatized. The first step to remedying this problem is recognizing it and making an effort to become educated on homelessness.

So next time a homeless person asks you for help, don't pretend like they don't exist. Instead, strike up a conversation with them.

Who knows, you might just learn something.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>58</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2018-10-28 00:10:50</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2018-10-28 00:10:50</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2018-10-28 01:04:00</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2018-10-28 01:04:00</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>hope-for-the-homeless</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1540685453]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[23654762462]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The Role of Standardized Tests in the Perpetuation of the Achievement Gap</title>
  <link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog/2019/04/03/the-role-of-standardized-tests-in-the-perpetuation-of-the-achievement-gap/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 02:19:18 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>tinahhong</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepassionpost.home.blog/?p=74</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[In the nineteenth century, eugenicists believed that race determined intelligence, and they created IQ tests to help them confirm this. In a journal from Washington University, civil rights activist W.E.B. DuBois was quoted as saying that these IQ tests were administered to “put black folk absolutely beyond the possibility of civilization” (Au). These tests were influential in the development of the Scholastic Aptitude Test (SAT), which the College Board claimed could measure innate intelligence and the capacity to learn. The SAT was put into the education system in the 1930s by the president of Harvard University, James B. Conant. Conant adopted this test into the Harvard’s admissions process under the belief that it would allow access to an elite education to be based on academic ability rather than wealth or family background, which would allow for the growth of a true meritocracy (Ferguson). However, the results from the SAT then mirrored the achievement gap today: Asian people score better than white people, white people score an average of 100 points more than African Americans, and even men score better than women on the math portion. These results seem to confirm the ideas of racists and eugenicists, and by claiming to be an objective measure of intelligence, the test has solidified and contributed to the many stereotypes about the academic inferiority of certain races today. Critics of the SAT have prompted the College Board to remove the word “aptitude” from the test name, and eventually the whole acronym. Ironically, a test that Conant believed would provide economic and social mobility to underprivileged people backfired, as today it is used to justify the disproportionate population of privileged people in elite academic institutions. While the causes of the achievement gap are still controversial, it isn’t surprising that standardized tests result in segregation today considering the SAT’s role in racism and eugenics.

There are many factors that influence one’s “developed reasoning”— the quality that the  College Board claims that the SAT measures—many of which give a disproportionately large advantage to affluent white students. For example, according to the founder of the test prep company Applerouth, Jed Appelrouth, and Georgia State professor Karen Zabrucky, around 14 to 34 percent of the ethnic SAT score gap may result from differences in parental education. With America’s history of de jure segregation and discrimination ending only a few generations ago, white parents today collectively hold higher degrees than Black and Latino parents. In fact, according to data from U.S News &amp; Ranking Report, only 19 percent of African American adults held a Bachelor’s degree or higher in 2013, compared to more than a third of white adults (“U.S. Education”). This discrepancy only serves to perpetuate the SAT score gap, and with the SAT’s large role in college admissions, it may hinder minority students from catching up with their white peers.

Furthermore, there is a high correlation between SAT scores and socioeconomic status. Zachary Goldfarb, the Deputy Business Editor of <i>The Washington Post</i>, found that students from families with annual incomes of at least $200,000 average 388 more points on the old SAT (out of 2400) than students from families earning under $20,000 a year (Goldfarb).

In this case, wealth allows families to afford more tutoring and test preparation services for their students, as well as better schools with qualified teachers that can better develop their critical reasoning and math skills. This trend disproportionately harms Black and Hispanic students, as they are more likely to be poor than white and Asian students, which is shown in the figure below (“U.S. Education”).

<img class=" size-full wp-image-75 aligncenter" src="https://thepassionposthome.files.wordpress.com/2019/03/stat.png" alt="stat" width="512" height="288" />

Many other factors may influence SAT scores as well, including neighborhood safety, access to technology, parental availability and advocacy, family structure, and others. But overall, many of these factors work against minority students, instead combining to grant affluent white students a level of cultural and social capital that provides educational advantages that enable them to perform better on standardized tests than low income and minority students. For this reason, many educators perceive that the score gap on standardized tests isn’t an objective measure of a students’ potential to learn and achieve, rather, it is a reflection of an opportunity gap.

Beyond college admissions tests, the implementation of the systematic use of high-stakes standardized tests in primary and secondary schools has fundamentally reshaped the climate of education for low-income and minority students by redefining standards of success. On January 8, 2002, President Bush signed the No Child Left Behind Act (NCLB), a piece of legislation that required all third through eighth grade students to reach a state-determined level of proficiency in a standardized math and reading assessment by a certain year. Bruce Webb, the author of “Encyclopedia of Race and Racism,” found that the results of one test can never be valid or substantial enough to use as the basis for large decisions regarding a student’s education. Despite this, NCLB imposed harsh sanctions on schools that failed to meet these requirements, as well as students, who were required to repeat the grade if they did not reach proficiency.

Under constant pressure of government intervention, schools began to center their education around standardized test preparation. Because NCLB expected students to raise their standardized test scores without providing the means for them to do so, teachers in impoverished schools with minority students, in particular, spent months preparing students for these tests instead of adhering to the normal curriculum. This was especially necessary because under NCLB, minority students were disproportionately repeating grades. In fact, an article from the International Education Journal maintains that since the inception of this act, twice as many African Americans and Latino students as white students have had to repeat grades in Texas (Au). Because standardized tests have occupied such a large niche in the education system, the quality of education has shifted away from creativity and individualism, and now rewards students who have mastered the ability to solve multiple-choice problems the way that standardized tests want them to. This transition prevails especially in schools with a high percentage of low-income and minority students, who face greater pressure to improve their scores. Overall, the implementation of high-stakes standardized tests has been met with harsh criticism, as a 2012 Gallup Poll shows that around 30 percent of Americans believe that NCLB has worsened the quality of education (Saad).

By using standardized test scores as the chief metric in determining academic success, schools and communities have seen increased levels of white-flight, and the resegregation of schools and communities. One of the old requirements of NCLB was that students from schools that failed to reach a level of proficiency for two years in a row were allowed to transfer to better-performing schools in the same district. Because chronically underfunded schools with a majority of minority students tend to score lower on these tests, these districts have seen a rise in the number of higher-income white families leaving their community and taking even more funds with them. In fact, a report from the U.S. Government Accountability Office found that from the 2000-01 to the 2013-14 school year, the percentage of schools with more than 75 percent racial and socioeconomic minorities has grown from 9 to 16 percent (“Better Use”). Levels of white-flight have increased because lower test scores have become synonymous with a lower academic ability of students, and thus many ranking websites use this information as the primary measure of school quality. Because many low-income and minority students have less opportunities to succeed on these tests, higher-income white families often move to other schools where they believe that their children will have better opportunities to succeed. While these parents are acting in what they believe are for the best interest of their children, they’re being misled when standardized tests are used as the chief metric of the quality of education. According to historian and political activist, Jack Schneider, who earned his Ph.D in education at Stanford University, poor family and neighborhood conditions attribute more to the test score gap than the actual quality of schools, as the former factor may account for 60 percent of the gap, while teachers only account for around 10 percent. This means that families are moving because they are misled into believing that standardized test scores are an accurate indicator of school quality.

As urban areas resegregate, schools and neighborhoods are losing even more funds necessary for them to tackle the task of closing the opportunity gap. This trend has harmed efforts to close the score gap, as these racially and socioeconomically isolated schools offer fewer college preparatory courses, and often poorer instruction. These schools can afford less educational resources, such as tutors, technology, or books, to adequately supplement and enhance the learning experience for their students. In a <i>Phi Delta Kappan </i>journal, Jerry Rosiek, who works at the University of Oregon’s Department of Education Studies, describes the many consequences of attending a racially or socioeconomically isolated school, which include lower standardized test scores, graduation rates, rates of college attendance, and wealth and income accumulation over generations. These trends are not caused by a lower level of effort or innate intelligence on the part of the students. Instead, Rosiek argues that the results are strongly correlated with the lower amounts of money spent per student. Therefore, the lower levels of performance in racially and socioeconomically isolated schools are a consequence of the way resources and opportunities follow white students.

Another reason for the rising level of segregation in neighborhoods and schools is the reinforcement of stigmas against low achieving minority students resulting from test scores. In their book <i>Despite the Best Intentions,</i> Amanda Lewis and John Diamond explain how many privileged families believe in achievement ideology, the concept that their students receive high test scores based on their own merit, and that minority students struggle as a result of a lack of commitment to their education. Much of this mindset mirrors “culture of poverty” arguments that ignore institutional shortcomings that place people in unfavorable conditions, and instead shift the blame on the low-income and minority students themselves. Those who believe this fail to realize that our education system isn’t a perfect meritocracy, as there are many structural factors seriously disadvantage low income and minority students, such as the underfunding of schools and the lower quality of teachers in some urban areas. Beyond merely effort, academic success requires a supplement of ample opportunities, and the resources to make the most of both. Therefore, high-stakes standardized tests cannot be the a fair measure of success, as the illusion of the educational system as a fair meritocracy creates a narrative that the discrepancy in standardized test scores is a product of the shortcoming of minority students, which perpetuates stereotypes that lead to the racial and socioeconomic stratification of neighborhoods and schools.

Negative stereotypes about the academic ability of minority students leads to their overrepresentation in lower academic tracks. Schools that receive lower levels of funding have less rigorous classes such as Advanced Placement courses, and the number of students who take these tests is not nearly reflective of the demography of the nation. The College Board reported that while students in the country who qualified for free or reduced-price meals—an indicator of poverty—represented nearly 50 percent of high-schoolers, they only accounted for 27 percent of AP test-takers. Furthermore, a national ProPublica study of over 50 million students shows that white students are 1.8 times as likely as Black students to be in an Advanced Placement class (Groeger et al.). Regardless of their socioeconomic status, a disproportionate number of minority students attend these lower-funded schools, and even affluent Black and Latino students in wealthier districts are underrepresented in these higher tracks than their white and Asian counterparts.

The reasons for this racial and socioeconomic stratification of classrooms may include the use of standardized tests for placement into advanced classes and the role of subjective parental and teacher referrals that are often influenced by negative racial stereotypes about minority students. The unequal placement of Black and Latino students in lower tracks only exacerbates the achievement gap, as advanced classes are often taught by better teachers, have more rigorous coursework, and expect more from students. In fact, Professor Stephen Kotok, who holds a PhD in Educational Theory and Policy, argues that lower placement may even harm students, as over time, students in higher tracks show greater gains in performance than those in lower tracks. The racial stratification of our classrooms show that while many schools may have desegregated, classrooms aren’t quite integrated yet, and until they are, the achievement gap will persist and widen over time.

The lower expectations set for minority students by teachers and peers often discourage them from reaching their full academic potentials. Many stereotypes have ingrained themselves into our culture after the de jure segregation in the past, which has either banned black students from schools, or put them in separate and unequal classrooms after Brown vs. Board made it unconstitutional to establish separate schools for different races. After such a prevailing history of discrimination and the deprivation of opportunities, the stereotypes and stigmas that have formed as a result are still prevalent today. These stereotypes may be subconsciously influencing how teachers judge the aptitude and ability of their students. In fact, these subtle racial biases may change the way we view others on a daily basis, even if we believe that we live in a post-racial era. As a result, people whose academic potentials are often negatively stigmatized often report that they have to perform at higher levels to be judged as equally competent as people who aren’t stigmatized (Diamond and Lewis). But beyond the fact that the lower expectations that teachers may set for minority students results in their placement in lower tracks, these lower expectations may also create self-fulfilling prophecies that widen the achievement gap. The co-author of the<i> Encyclopedia of Mental Health and Mental Disorders</i> analyzes a notable study where it was found that the expectations that teachers had of their students affected the way they behaved towards them, so that when random students were assigned the label “academically gifted,” their teachers were more academically nurturing and demanding of them. This directly resulted in their higher gains in reading levels and standardized test scores (Vensel). The implications of these findings are large, as the negative social perceptions regarding the academic potentials of Black and Latino students may directly influence outcomes in ways that continue to reinforce existing stereotypes.

The racial stratification of classrooms not only impacts the way that teachers view minority students, but it also influences the psychological esteem and aspirations for the students themselves. Minority students who are constantly reminded of the negative stereotypes regarding their academic potentials, and who see the racial composition of classrooms seem to confirm this, may start to internalize these stereotypes. As a result, they may adopt lower expectations and aspirations for themselves. At the same time, those within a stigmatized group are often afraid of fitting into the stereotype in ways that might confirm it to others, and as a result they may develop anxiety and distance themselves from the academic process entirely. In fact, even asking students to state their race on a standardized test may induce anxiety that lowers their performance. The <i>Encyclopedia of Race and Racism </i>describes this phenomenon as “stereotype threat” (Webb).

Over time, as stereotypes continue to insidiously influence the way that minority students are perceived and treated at school, they may choose to distance themselves from the institution to protect their sense of identity. Rodolfo Mendoza-Denton, a psychology professor at the University of California, Berkeley, conducted a study in which he found that students who believed that their professors might discriminate against them were less likely to let their esteem be impacted by their academic outcomes. Moreover, these students were less welcoming of feedback from the professor. This is problematic because the less invested a student is in the academic process, and the less trust they have with their professor, the less growth they will exhibit over time. Minority students who see racially stratified classrooms, who are the recipients of lower expectations, and who are constantly reminded of the stereotypes that standardized tests perpetuate by presenting an “objective” measure of future academic success, are more inclined to dissociate themselves from the academic institution entirely—not only to avoid being stereotyped, but also because they possibly never saw themselves as a fully welcomed member of the institution in the first place. Thus, there are a host of institutional and sociological factors that cause and maintain the achievement gap.

The disjointing effects that standardized tests have on educational quality extend past high school as well, specifically in the college admissions process. According to information from the National Association for College Admission Counseling (NACAC), 88 percent of four-year colleges and universities place a moderate or considerable amount of importance on standardized tests in their admissions processes (Appelrouth and Zabrucky). The large weight that standardized tests hold in the admissions process makes it necessary to verify the effectiveness of these tests at predicting future academic success. The NACAC conducted a study and found that high school grade point average had a far higher correlation with first year college grades than any portion of the SAT did. Moreover, the correlation between students’ first year college success and their standardized test scores varied widely from school to school, meaning that the accuracy of the SAT and other college-admissions tests on predicting academic potential isn’t definite enough to justify the amount of consideration that universities give them in admissions processes.

On the other hand, because the SAT and ACT are standardized tests, their results may be easier to interpret than GPA at times. A finalist for the Pulitzer Prize, Maureen Downey, warns against rising levels of grade inflation, a phenomenon often measured by the disparities between grades and standardized tests, such as state-administered tests or Advanced Placement tests. Downey cites questionable statistics in a few districts in Georgia, where graduation rates are increasing while scores on state exams administered at the end of different courses are declining, suggesting that teachers have been lowering their standards of grading and handing out better grades even though the students may not have truly earned them. This means that the amount of effort that some students would need to put in to earn a B at one school could be enough to earn them an A in another, which ultimately renders grades less informative for colleges. Additionally, Downey argues that grade inflation is more prevalent in private schools and wealthier public schools, and that parental pressure may be influencing grade inflation in more affluent schools with a majority of white students.

Regardless, it is essential to remember that standardized tests aren’t an objective measure of academic potential, and that it isn’t fair to judge all students based on the same set of standards when they aren’t given the same opportunities or resources to reach them. Therefore, the overreliance on tests in tracking and admissions processes can deprive qualified people of better educational opportunities, and thus standardized tests should only be, at max, used as a supplement to other holistic factors. According to Dr. Ivory Toldson and Tyne McGee from Howard University, some colleges rely on these tests too heavily, as some may have restrictive ACT or SAT cutoff scores. For example, while the requirements to be considered for Southern University and A&amp;M College in Baton Rouge, are a 2.0 GPA and a 20 on the ACT, the average high school GPA among Black students is 2.7, but the average ACT score among Black students is 17. This means that even if a student maintains at least four years of learning and working habits to maintain a certain GPA, they will still be denied in favor of one three hour standardized test that isn’t that significantly valid. This only serves to prolong the socioeconomic achievement gap, since those who cannot afford test preparation, or to take the test multiple times, are more likely to score short of the cutoffs.

Furthermore, the use of standardized tests as an objective measure of academic potential has seemingly legitimized the post-racial ideology that impedes efforts to address the achievement gap. Recently, a lawsuit filed against Harvard University has put the policy of affirmative action, or race-conscious admissions, under fire. Jeannie Gerson, a professor at the Harvard Law School, argues that while the number of Asian students living in America since the 1990s has doubled, the amount of Asians in each freshman class has remained at 16 to 19 percent. Furthermore, she cites an old study done by Princeton University, where it was found that Asians had to score 140 points higher on the SAT than white students to have the same chance of admission at top universities. Using the supposed objectivity of standardized tests as a basis for many of their claims, the Students for Fair Admissions (SFFA) have used these statistics to accuse Harvard of discriminating against Asian students. SSFA hopes to eliminate race as an admissions factor all together, as California did in 1996 with Proposition 209. Since the implementation of this proposition, former United States Secretary of Health and Human Services, Tom Price, claims that the representation of Black students in the freshman classes at the University of California’s Berkeley and Los Angeles campuses went from 8 percent in 1995 to 2.8 and 4.3 percent in 2015, respectively. If SFFA is to succeed in their case against Harvard, then schools would begin to rely more on “objective” measures of academic potential, such as the SAT or ACT, which would cause the diversity in many of the elite colleges to decrease dramatically.

However, a system that is meant to address previous centuries of systematic oppression cannot be eliminated from the college admissions process until the education system is truly post-racial. There are still many institutional barriers that reinforce the ethnic disparities in academic achievement, including the tracking programs that are affected by stigmas about the academic competency of minority students, the chronic underfunding of urban schools with a majority of minority students, and the use of standardized tests as an objective measure of future levels of achievement. Until these are addressed, preferential treatment towards minority students is necessary to compensate for the racism and discrimination that has caused the achievement gap, as higher education is the best asset for socioeconomic mobility.

Today, hundreds of schools have adopted test-optional admissions policies. Nick Anderson, a veteran education journalist for <i>The Washington Post</i>, reports that underrepresented students of color are more likely to apply to and enroll in schools that have test-optional admissions policies, and that students who didn’t submit standardized test scores were just as likely to graduate as students who did. These findings suggest that policies that require students to submit their standardized test scores act as a barrier between qualified students who didn’t have the resources to prepare as well for these tests, and their chances of realizing their college aspirations. Test-optional policies can help reverse the trend of the underrepresentation of minorities in elite colleges. Recently, the University of Chicago became the first elite institution to make standardized test scores optional in the admissions process. Anderson quotes John Boyer, the dean of the undergraduate college, who claimed that the university did this so that elite education could be equally accessible for “all citizens, not just those born in certain Zip codes.”

Furthermore, the benefits of socioeconomic and ethnic diversity are shared by all people. Joanne Williams, an expert on race and ethnicity as social contexts for youth development, explains that diverse schools often exhibit less of an ethnic score gap, and have more equitable access to educational resources. Furthermore, exposure to such diversity shatters stereotypes, and allows students to develop unbiased attitudes towards members of different ethnic groups (“Understanding the Benefits”). Learning in more colorful environments prepares students to enter diverse workforces and communities, and allows for the progression towards a truly post-racial society.

&nbsp;

<hr />

&nbsp;
<p style="text-align:center;">Works Cited:</p>
<em>The 10th Annual AP Report to the Nation</em>. 11 Feb. 2014. <em>College Board</em>, media.collegeboard.com/digitalServices/pdf/ap/rtn/10th-annual/10th-annual-ap-report-to-the-nation-single-page.pdf. Accessed 6 Mar. 2019.

Anderson, Nick. "University of Chicago Eliminates SAT/ACT Requirement." <em>Washington Post</em>, 14 Jun. 2018, pp. A.2<em>. SIRS Issues Researcher.</em> http://sks.sirs.com/webapp/article?artno=0000407069&amp;type=ART. Accessed 28 Feb. 2019.

Appelrouth, Jed I., and Karen M. Zabrucky. "Preparing for the SAT: A Review." <em>College and University</em>, vol. 92, no. 1, 2017, pp. 2-8,10-14,16-17<em>. ProQuest</em>, https://search.proquest.com/docview/1901677556?accountid=36487. Accessed 6 Mar. 2019.

Au, Wayne. "Hiding behind High-Stakes Testing: Meritocracy, Objectivity and Inequality in U.S. Education." <em>International Education Journal</em>, vol. 12, no. 2, 2013, pp. 7-20. <em>ERIC PlusText</em>, eric.ed.gov/?id=EJ1017702. Accessed 1 Mar. 2019.

"Better Use of Information Could Help Agencies Identify Disparities and Address Racial Discrimination." <em>U.S. Government Accountability Office</em>, 21 Apr. 2016, www.gao.gov/products/GAO-16-345. Accessed 3 Mar. 2019.

Downey, Maureen. <em>Grade Inflation on the Rise: Everybody Gets an A.</em> Cox Newspapers, Inc, Atlanta, 2018<em>. ProQuest</em>, https://search-proquest-com.newtrier.idm.oclc.org/docview/2133070508?accountid=36487. Accessed 9 Mar. 2019.

Ferguson, Andrew. "The SAT and its Enemies." <em>Weekly Standard Vol.14, No.31</em>, May. 2009, pp. 18-27<em>. SIRS Issues Researcher</em>, https://sks.sirs.com. Accessed 12 Mar. 2019.

Gersen, Jeannie Suk. "The Uncomfortable Truth About Affirmative Action and Asian-Americans." <em>The New Yorker</em>, 27 Aug. 2017, www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-uncomfortable-truth-about-affirmative-action-and-asian-americans. Accessed 28 Feb. 2019.

Goldfarb, Zachary. "These Four Charts Show How the SAT Favors Rich, Educated Families." <em>The Atlantic</em>, 5 Mar. 2014, www.washingtonpost.com/. Accessed 7 Mar. 2019.

Groeger, Lena, et al. "Is There Racial Inequality at Your School?" <em>Miseducation</em>, ProPublica, 16 Oct. 2018, projects.propublica.org/miseducation?utm_source=pardot&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=dailynewsletter. Accessed 6 Mar. 2019.

Karlson, Kristian Bernt. "Expectations on Track? High School Tracking and Adolescent Educational Expectations." <em>Special Forces</em>, vol. 94, no. 1, Sept. 2015, pp. 115-41. <em>JSTOR</em>, www.jstor.org. Accessed 26 Feb. 2019.

Kotok, Stephen. "Unfulfilled Potential: High-Achieving Minority Students and the High School Achievement Gap in Math." <em>The High School Journal</em>, vol. 100, no. 3, 2017, pp183–202. <em>JSTOR</em>, www.jstor.org/stable/90024211. Accessed 4 Mar. 2019.

Lewis, Amanda, and John Diamond. <em>Despite the Best Intentions: How Racial Inequality Thrives in Good Schools</em>. Oxford University Press, 2016.

Mendoza-Denton, Rodolfo. "A Social Psychological Perspective on the Achievement Gap in Standardized Test Performance between White and Minority Students: Implications for Assessment." <em>The Journal of Negro Education</em>, vol. 83, no. 4, 2014, pp. 465-484<em>. ProQuest.</em> https://search.proquest.com/docview/1684189644/F7E6DF9469F44A45PQ/1?accountid=36487. Accessed 28 Feb. 2019.

Price, Tom. "Affirmative Action and College Admissions." <em>CQ Researcher</em>, 17 Nov. 2017, pp. 969-92. http://library.cqpress.com/cqresearcher/document.php?id=cqresrre2017111700&amp;type=hitlist&amp;num=0. Accessed 28 Feb. 2019.

Rosiek, Jerry. "School Segregation: A Realist's View." <em>Phi Delta Kappan</em>, 21 Jan. 2019, www.kappanonline.org/school-segregation-realists-view-rosiek/. Accessed 28 Feb. 2019.

Saad, Lydia. "No Child Left Behind Rated More Negatively Than Positively." <em>GALLUP</em>, 20 Aug. 2012. <em>GALLUP</em>, news.gallup.com/poll/156800/no-child-left-behind-rated-negatively-positively.aspx. Accessed 3 Mar. 2019.

Schneider, Jack. "The Urban-School Stigma." <em>The Atlantic</em>, 25 Aug. 2015, www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2017/08/the-urban-school-stigma/537966/. Accessed 26 Feb. 2019.

Toldson, Ivory A. and Tyne McGee. "What the ACT and SAT Mean for Black Students' Higher Education Prospects." <em>The Journal of Negro Education</em>, vol. 83, no. 1, 2014, pp. 1–4. <em>JSTOR</em>, www.jstor.org/stable/10.7709/jnegroeducation.83.1.0001. Accessed 26 Feb. 2019

"Understanding the Benefits of School Diversity in the.." <em>Targeted News Service</em>, 2018, pp. n/a<em>. SIRS Issues Researcher</em>, https://sks-sirs-com.newtrier.idm.oclc.org. Accessed 7 Mar. 2019.

"U.S. Education: Still Separate and Unequal." <em>The Civic Report</em>, edited by Lindsey Cook, U.S News &amp; World Report, 25 Jan. 2015, www.usnews.com/news/blogs/data-mine/2015/01/28/us-education-still-separate-and-unequal. Accessed 3 Mar. 2019.

<em>Use of Predictive Validity Studies to Inform Admission Practices</em>. National Association for College Admission Counseling, 2016. <em>National Association for College Admission Counseling</em>, www.nacacnet.org/globalassets/documents/publications/research/testvalidity.pdf. Accessed 7 Mar. 2019.

Vensel, Steven R., PhD. "Self-Fulfilling Prophecy." <em>Mental Health and Mental Disorders</em>: <em>An Encyclopedia of Conditions, Treatments, and Well-Being</em>, edited by Len Sperry, vol. 3, Greenwood, 2016, pp. 999-1000. <em>Gale Virtual Reference Library.</em> www.go.galegroup.com. Accessed 28 Feb. 2019.

Webb, Bruce. "Standardized Tests." <em>Encyclopedia of Race and Racism</em>, edited by Patrick L. Mason, 2nd ed., vol. 4, Macmillan Reference USA, 2013, pp. 128-130. <em>Gale Virtual Reference Library.</em> www.go.galegroup.com. Accessed 28 Feb. 2019.

Westervelt, Eric. "College Applicants Sweat The SATs. Perhaps They Shouldn't." <em>National Public Radio</em>, 18 Feb. 2014, www.npr.org. Accessed 26 Feb. 2019.]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>74</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2019-04-03 02:19:18</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2019-04-03 02:19:18</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2019-04-03 02:19:18</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2019-04-03 02:19:18</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-role-of-standardized-tests-in-the-perpetuation-of-the-achievement-gap</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[73]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_pending</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_wp_old_date</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[2019-03-16]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[29335066837]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1554257964]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The Psychology of Baby Brain Development</title>
  <link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog/2020/01/08/the-psychology-of-baby-brain-development/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 01:49:24 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>tinahhong</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepassionpost.home.blog/?p=81</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[The distance from a mother's crooked elbow to the wide eyes of their newborn baby matches the range of the baby's field of vision perfectly. This clever design by nature assures that the baby's brain can easily form neural networks to create an emotional connection to the caregiver.

A newborn baby's brain is primed to form as many synaptic connections as it can. Every little stimulus that a baby perceives in its first few months will cause its brain to reorganize and grow more complex. The wondrous mobile rotating over a baby's eyes causes connections to form within the brain's visual cortex; the gentle bouncing or rocking of a baby creates new synaptic connections within the motor cortex.

Any form of play or stimuli causes the basic foundations of a baby's brain to grow and develop, and these complex connections compound and strengthen through adolescence and into adulthood, at which point the brain harbors well over 100 trillion connections.

The first years are especially crucial for brain development. Within these years, there are certain windows in which an abundant amount of stimulus is essential for the full development of certain skills and senses. These critical time windows have a beginning and an ending point, after which, the associated brain areas become less malleable, and development may be impaired.

For example, the circuit for vision grows the most when the baby is around eight months old. This corresponds to exactly when the baby begins to become more curious about their visual surroundings. A baby that has cataracts in their eyes and is deprived of any visual stimuli during the critical period in the visual system, which closes after a few years, may be permanently blind even after the cataracts are removed.

Similarly, after only about a year, a baby's neural auditory map is nearly fully formed. The baby soon loses the ability to discriminate between sounds outside of their native language, and the intonations and sounds of their native language are incorporated into their cries and gibberish. Children taught a second or third language after the age of 10 will have a much harder time learning how to speak like a native. It's no wonder that school districts that begin teaching foreign&nbsp;languages in high school find low fluency and&nbsp;retention rates within their students.

Similarly, musical artists who began playing string instruments at very young ages develop many more somatosensory cortexes dedicated to the fingers they use to play their instruments than those who begin playing later. This jump-start on their instrument playing allows them to appear like a "natural" at the instrument that they play, and with continual practice, this&nbsp;may offer them a permanent edge over those who started later.

A healthy amount of sensory stimulation in babies is essential for healthy development. In studies done on rats, those placed in environments with playmates, toys, and other stimuli grew around 25 percent more synaptic connections than rats deprived of such stimuli. While the exact correspondence to human brain development isn't clear, human babies exhibit similar synaptic growth in the presence of sensory stimuli. These stimuli can be found in the form of toys, playing peek-a-boo, listening to others talk to them, mobiles, music, and others. The need for these stimuli emphasizes the importance of good attentive parenting, as well as strong early childhood education. It's vital that we give babies the attention and stimulus they need so that everyone who enters into the world can be nurtured to a future of happiness and fulfillment.

Think of the&nbsp;simple newborn&nbsp;staring up with a wide gaping mouth at a swirling mobile above it. While we often&nbsp;smile and coo at the cute baby staring in what seems like clueless awe of the technology above it, we often overlook the significance of these moments of awe and&nbsp;play. It's during these experiences that the baby's brain is methodically rewiring and firing,&nbsp;in complex ways that we may not fully understand, in order to lay down the blueprint for the rest of the baby's life.

&nbsp;

<hr>

Works Cited:

Begley, Sharon. “Your Child's Brain.” <i>Newsweek</i>, 13 Mar. 2010, www.newsweek.com/your-childs-brain-179930.

<span>Bryan M. Hooks, Chinfei Chen, C</span><span>ritical Periods in the Visual System: Changing Views for a Model of Experience-Dependent Plasticity, Neuron, Volume 56, Issue 2, 2007, Pages 312-326.</span>

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>81</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-01-08 01:49:24</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-01-08 01:49:24</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-02-23 16:29:51</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-02-23 16:29:51</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-psychology-of-baby-brain-development</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[111]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1578448167]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[39291662566]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
</item>

<item>
  <title>The Future Is 2020: My Goals</title>
  <link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog/2020/01/06/the-future-is-2020-my-goals/</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 04:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>tinahhong</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepassionpost.home.blog/?p=87</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[During the 2020th revolution of the Earth around the Sun since the birth of Jesus Christ, I will be turning 18, graduating high school, and moving away for college. In short, this year is going to be one of many big decisions, and hopefully, a lot of growth.

As much as I say that senioritis is going to hit me second semester, I've grown so accustomed to working hard that I don't know if I'll consciously be willing to let off the gas pedal. However, I do hope to study a little less and focus more on personal growth. One way that I'll measure this growth is by setting goals for me to <span style="display:inline !important;float:none;background-color:#ffffff;color:#2c3338;cursor:text;font-family:'Noto Serif', Georgia, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif;font-size:16px;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;font-weight:400;letter-spacing:normal;line-height:1.2em;orphans:2;text-align:left;text-decoration:none;text-indent:0;text-transform:none;white-space:normal;word-spacing:0;">achieve and habits for me to form.</span>

During this second semester of my senior year and this last summer at home, I hope to accomplish the following things (they're listed in no particular order). I'll periodically post updates on how I'm progressing in each goal, but feel free to check up on me and keep me accountable!

Second semester/Summer goals and habits:
<ul>
	<li>Learn to play guitar:
<ul>
	<li>I got a guitar for Christmas last year, and I taught myself a few chords, but I have yet to learn a full song, or how to freestyle to any acoustic song.</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Learn to sing:
<ul>
	<li>I sing at my church sometimes but have never taken lessons or gotten much feedback from anyone. I hope to expand my range and learn how to control my breathing. I hope to grow comfortable enough singing in front of anyone, and I hope I get to lead more at church.</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Update this blog once every other week:
<ul>
	<li>I haven't posted on here in quite a few months, but from now on I hope to post regularly. I see many benefits of blogging. For one, it keeps me thinking. By posting once every two weeks, I'll have to master a new concept, current event, or skill in order to blog about it. Or, I can blog about myself. In doing so, I'll obtain the benefits gained from journaling, such as learning more about my goals, motivations, personality, emotions, intrinsic beliefs and biases, etc. I hope to make this a habit. Feel free to help me by commenting any suggestions for topics that you would like to see me post about!</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Read a book every month:
<ul>
	<li>Later I may blog a list of books that I've been wanting to read, but I've often felt too busy to read books. I hope during the beginning of this new year that I can return to my old habits of reading too much every day. The first book I want to read is <em>Educated </em>by Tara Westover.</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Listen to a Podcast every day
<ul>
	<li>I have <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/6HCecASlhCo2XwFcSAOmsN" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a list of educational podcasts to listen to</a>. I listen to music pretty much whenever I'm not sleeping, so I hope to substitute some of that music for podcasts so that I can learn something extra every day.</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Learn how to cook:
<ul>
	<li>How else am I gonna survive college? But also, I want to learn how to make these following dishes, among others, just to be able to eat them whenever I want:
<ul>
	<li>Pho</li>
	<li>Ramen</li>
	<li>Pork Buns</li>
	<li>Banana Pancakes</li>
	<li>Homemade Pasta</li>
	<li>Dakjuk</li>
	<li>Wonton</li>
	<li>Banana Bread/Pumpkin Bread</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Learn how to dance:
<ul>
	<li>Another good social skill to have! I always feel awkward when I dance, so I hope I can improve for future mosh pits and silent discos.</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Learn more Chinese:
<ul>
	<li>Fun fact about my family: my parents speak to my siblings and me in Mandarin, but we always reply in English. Because of this, I can understand spoken mandarin very well, but I don't know how to speak too well, and I hope to speak to them in Chinese more because being bilingual is pretty important.</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Learn some Spanish:
<ul>
	<li>Being trilingual would be cooler though. So hello Duolingo!</li>
</ul>
</li>
	<li>Lose some weight:
<ul>
	<li>Basketball is going to end soon, maybe indefinitely, so I'll need to find another way to stay in shape.</li>
	<li>Beyond exercising, I hope to cut down on the amount of added sugars that I eat.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>87</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-01-06 04:09:29</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-01-06 04:09:29</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-01-07 02:29:37</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-01-07 02:29:37</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>the-future-is-2020-my-goals</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1578283772]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[39218379945]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>22</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[marissasun]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>sunmarissa15@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url/>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>73.211.134.51</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2020-01-06 04:42:22</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2020-01-06 04:42:22</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[These are some pretty sick goals and I’m for sure going to hold you  accountable :)]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>177910526</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1578285743.073418;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:10:"marissasun";}]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>email_notification_notqueued</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1578285969]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1578285969]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1578285969.837514;s:5:"event";s:15:"status-approved";s:4:"user";s:9:"tinahhong";}]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>comment_like_count</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>23</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[tinahhong]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>tinahhong@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url>http://uwu.com</wp:comment_author_url>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>73.210.204.149</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2020-01-07 02:58:47</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2020-01-07 02:58:47</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[darn. this bish is illiterate



but she got a nice ass tho]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>0</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>0</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1578365928.455823;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:2:{s:4:"time";d:1578370550.565103;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";}]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Policy In The Alleviation of The Achievement Gap: Head Start</title>
  <link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog/2020/01/15/policy-in-the-alleviation-of-the-achievement-gap-head-start/</link>
  <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 04:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>tinahhong</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepassionpost.home.blog/?p=117</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[In Lyndon B. Johnson’s 1964 State of the Union Address, he shared his vision for a War on Poverty. As part of this, he planned to develop a program to prepare low-income children for elementary school. A major issue in the perpetuation of poverty is inequity in the quality of education, so Johnson appointed agencies and experts to develop child development programs to help low-income and disadvantaged communities provide better early childhood education. The transition from preschool to elementary school imposes diverse developmental challenges that include requiring the children to engage successfully with their peers outside the family network, adjust to the space of a classroom, and meet the expectations the school setting provides. Johnson’s large comprehensive program that tackled these issues eventually became known as the Head Start program.

Head Start was intended to be a wide-ranging program that would provide low-income families resources to prepare their children for school. This was heavily influenced by the philosophy that children require holistic development. Therefore, the program was intended to address early learning, health, and parent involvement. Within childhood education, the program stressed many aspects of learning, including play, interactions with adults, and planned instruction. Alongside this, children would develop social skills by being around fellow students. To support health, the policy helped families access medical services. It also provided its own health screenings, nutritious meals, and mental health support. Lastly, to foster enriching family environments, the program would give parents guidance on how to reach their own goals, such as housing stability, continued education, and financial security. The program would also champion healthy parent-child relationships by advocating for parents to become involved in their child’s development.

In order to successfully solve the problems of all low-income families, Head Start needed to provide services to minority and at-risk groups. For example, Head Start aimed to reach children of migrant and seasonal farm workers by creating services specifically targeted to them. This program included longer hours each day, but it lasted for a shorter period. Similarly, Head Start sought to help indigenous Americans by creating centers on reservations and to specifically find and target homeless children. Later on, policy makers expanded their reach through Early Head Start, which sought to address the problem of school-readiness at an even earlier age. This meant supporting child development beginning as early as birth.

In order to facilitate these goals, Head Start planned to assign each child a Service Coordinator who would help assess the family’s situation and provide the required services. These early intervention services would help children receive tailored support.

Originally, the Office of Economic Opportunity's (OEO’s) Community Action Program launched Project Head Start as an eight-week summer program through Head Start Child Development Centers in 1965. The program was led by Dr. Robert Cooke, a respected pediatrician, and Dr. Edward Zigler, a professor and psychologist at Yale. It was intended to help communities meet the needs of disadvantaged preschool children. The OEO implemented many of the other programs included in the Great Society plan, including VISTA and Job Corps. It received government funding to carry out its initiatives. However, this appropriation of funding was later ruled unconstitutional in 1973.

Based on the success of the summer program, Congress authorized Head Start as a primarily part day, nine-month program. By 1965, Head Start organized the first school year programs. The following year it was authorized by Congress as a year–round program. In 1968, Head Start began funding a television series that would eventually become the show that all children know and love: Sesame Street.

The Government Accountability Office labeled Project Head Start a success in child development, but the GAO also influenced Head Start’s evolution. By releasing a report that found challenges in parent engagement within the program, the GAO’s analysis influenced Head Start to improve policies on parent participation.

The Office of Economic Opportunity is an agency in the Department of Commerce. Its major function during the War on Poverty was to innovate, experiment, and develop new approaches to the problems of poverty, so in 1969, after Project Head Start had generated substantial success, it was reassigned to the Department of Health, Education and Welfare, in the Office of Child Development, within the Children's Bureau.

In 1972, Congress amended the Economic Opportunity Act, mandating that at least 10 percent of Head Start’s national enrollment consist of handicapped children. Head Start collaborates with the Office of Education Bureau of Education for the Handicapped to fund offer technical assistance to Head Start teachers to help them work with handicapped children.

The McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act of 2001 required Head Start to allow homeless children and families access to early childhood education. During the 2007 reauthorization, homeless children were included explicitly as subjects of the program.

In response to public criticism about the positive benefits of Head Start fading out over time, as well as new scientific research emphasizing the importance of the first few years in child development, President Obama proposed a series of new investments during the 2013 State of the Union address that would establish access to high quality education for children between birth and the age of 5. These new investments included providing preschool for all, funding Early Head Start-Child Care partnerships, and expanding home visiting programs.

Overtime, Head start is continually expanding. Head Start’s federal budget has consistently increased over the years, peaking at $10 billion as of 2019. Every few years, the standards that the program holds for students and teachers is elevated, and the types of services it provides diversifies.

As the program continues to expand, statistics have shown that parents in the Head Start program report positive outcomes with their experience. A 2015 CCR Analytics survey, which reached 11,600 California Head Start parents, found that 90% of parents said Head Start aided them in finding a job and 99% reported that Head Start gave them key resources to assist their parenting. Evidently, parents see the beneficial impact of Head Start within their own families. However, further research on child outcomes is less clear-cut.

A study using data from the National Longitudinal Survey of Youth (NLSY) found that children in Head Start have an increased probability of graduating from high school and going to college. It was also found to have long-term social-emotional effects, helping Head Start students increase their self-esteem and regulate their emotions in adulthood. However, these findings may be called into question. Because Head Start children are among the most impoverished in the United States, meaning that (everything else being equal) they would be expected to achieve less than other students. As a result, it’s difficult to compare children in the Head Start program to a control group. According to an article in <i>The Atlantic, </i>the only long-term study of the program, called the Head Start Impact Study, began following enrollees in 2002 and stayed with them through third grade. Researchers found that by third grade, all the academic advances the children had made during their Head Start year had faded (Monegau).

It’s evident that research findings are often conflicting. One reason for Head Start’s struggles is that it doesn’t receive enough funding to entirely fulfill its mission. In 2014-15, only 41% of Head Start’s target population received its programs. Early Head Start, by comparison, reached only 3% of its population. Therefore, to reach all edible students, funding for Head Start and Early Head Start would need to increase enormously. Although, Head Start programs cost significantly less than comparable programs such as Perry Preschool and Carolina Abcedarian, so it provides more room for scaling if it were to receive additional funding.

Although Head Start hasn’t been able to support <i>all </i>eligible students, it has  succeeded in reaching a wide range of students, eventually expanding to support minorities such as Native Americans, children with disabilities, homeless children, and migrant. This is incredibly important because minority groups are often at high-risk for poverty and discrimination, and they are easily ignored by government programs.

Lastly, Head Start was founded to adapt to local situations, putting an emphasis on developing differently for different needs. However, Head Start still requires an extensive list of requirements for preschools. As a result, Head Start directors often report that they dedicate an exorbitant amount of time to document whether or not they comply with government regulations for preschools.

<span style="display:inline !important;float:none;background-color:#ffffff;color:#2c3338;cursor:text;font-family:'Noto Serif', Georgia, 'Times New Roman', Times, serif;font-size:16px;font-style:normal;font-variant:normal;font-weight:400;letter-spacing:normal;line-height:1.2em;orphans:2;text-align:left;text-decoration:none;text-indent:0;text-transform:none;white-space:normal;word-spacing:0;">Head Start is the largest comprehensive governmental program dedicated towards alleviating the achievement gap, and it </span>has had a significant impact on thousands of families over the course of its development. Although it faces challenges, like insufficient funding and spending excess resources on administrative oversight, its programs ultimately promote educational equity among America’s most vulnerable children. Furthermore, its holistic approach has had positive effects on parents, providing families with the resources to support their children’s education. Moving forward, more research must be undertaken to determine areas in which the program can continually improve.

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

<hr />

Works Cited

<a href="https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ohs/about/head-start">https://www.acf.hhs.gov/ohs/about/head-start</a>

<a href="http://www.child-encyclopedia.com/head-start-policy/according-experts/economic-impact-head-start">http://www.child-encyclopedia.com/head-start-policy/according-experts/economic-impact-head-start</a>

<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2016/08/is-head-start-a-failure/494942/">https://www.theatlantic.com/education/archive/2016/08/is-head-start-a-failure/494942/</a>

<a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/the-long-term-impact-of-the-head-start-program/">https://www.brookings.edu/research/the-long-term-impact-of-the-head-start-program/</a>

<a href="https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/blog/2015/05/18/day-history-creation-head-start">https://obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/blog/2015/05/18/day-history-creation-head-start</a>

<a href="https://www.nhsa.org/about-us/mission-vision-history">https://www.nhsa.org/about-us/mission-vision-history</a>

<a href="https://eclkc.ohs.acf.hhs.gov/about-us/article/head-start-timeline">https://eclkc.ohs.acf.hhs.gov/about-us/article/head-start-timeline</a>

<a href="https://www.thegravelygroup.com/resources/history-of-head-start/">https://www.thegravelygroup.com/resources/history-of-head-start/</a>

<a href="https://hechingerreport.org/is-head-start-a-failure/">https://hechingerreport.org/is-head-start-a-failure/</a>

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>117</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-01-15 04:35:06</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-01-15 04:35:06</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-01-15 04:39:00</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-01-15 04:39:00</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>policy-in-the-alleviation-of-the-achievement-gap-head-start</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1579062909]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[39557486151]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_thumbnail_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[123]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>24</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[marissasun]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>sunmarissa15@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url/>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>73.211.134.51</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2020-01-15 04:47:49</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2020-01-15 04:47:49</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[👍]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>177910526</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>email_notification_notqueued</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1579063672]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1579063670]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1579063671.38029;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:10:"marissasun";}]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>25</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[marissasun]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>sunmarissa15@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url/>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>73.211.134.51</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2020-01-15 04:48:01</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2020-01-15 04:48:01</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Nice work Tinah]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>177910526</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>comment_like_count</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[0]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>email_notification_notqueued</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1579063684]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1579063683.219012;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:10:"marissasun";}]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1579063682]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
</item>

<item>
  <title>First Gen Growth Mindset: A Mini Memoir</title>
  <link>http://thepassionpost.home.blog/2020/01/31/growth-and-first-gen-mindset-a-mini-memoir/</link>
  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 22:53:54 +0000</pubDate>
  <dc:creator>tinahhong</dc:creator>
  <guid isPermaLink="false">http://thepassionpost.home.blog/?p=127</guid>
  <description/>
  <content:encoded><![CDATA[<span style="color:#999999;"><em>Please note that this memoir is very personal. The goal of my blog was not only for it to educate others, but for it to help me learn more about myself. Writing became therapeutic as it helped me understand my emotions, personality and values better. So please read with an open mind, and feel free to comment if you have any reactions or questions. Thanks :)</em></span>

<hr />

&nbsp;

While my teammates were always disappointed whenever their parents couldn’t make it to one of their games, I felt my heart accelerate and a rush of adrenaline course through my veins when I spotted my dad walk into the gym during warmups to sit in the bleachers behind our bench. He never sat with the rest of the team parents. Instead, he always sat closest to me or closest to the basket that our team was scoring in so that he was in the optimal spot to heckle me.

From the moment that the ball tipped off he was already screaming in my ear.

“Attack!” He barked whenever I ran down on the side of the floor closest to him.

A grimace would spring up on my face whenever I heard him. I always tried to focus on the game and drown out the crowd, but his harsh voice pierced through the din of otherwise pleasant cheers. It became so unnerving that I ran up the side of the court furthest from him so that he wouldn’t scream across the gym.

The things that he screamed at me ranged from annoying to downright terrifying. They were usually spoken in a mix of broken English or Chinese, and he relied on the fact that there weren’t many other Chinese people on any basketball team to scream insults that he thought only I could understand.

“Nǐ zài bú dé fēn wǒ jiù huì dǎ sǐ nǐ!”

I nearly stopped mid-sprint when his words finally processed through my brain. My face unconsciously contorted in an expression of horror and embarrassment. I really hoped that none of the people in the gym understood Chinese, because hearing a parent scream death threats at their fifth-grade children during a basketball game is probably a little bit concerning.

Unlike the other teammates who went up to their parents right after games, I would always take care to trail behind my dad a few steps as we left the gym and walked to the parked car. The parking lot was quiet while my teammates trudged away after a disappointing loss. As my dad entered into the driver’s seat of our blue sedan, I lingered outside to soak in my last few seconds of quiet before ducking into the backseat with my little sister, Aimee.

Aimee and I sat stiffly in the backseat, the passenger seat besides our dad empty. I tried to avert my gaze from the rear view mirror, staring aimlessly out the window to avoid looking at the scowl ingrained on my dad’s face. But my eyes inevitably gravitated towards the mirror in anticipation of the upcoming lecture. Sure enough, I eventually saw his lips twitch in the mirror as he cleared his throat.

“Tinah, how many shots you take last game.”

I shut my eyes and took a deep breath: “I don’t know,” I exclaimed on the exhale. My response was almost inaudible.

“Three! You only take three shots.” My dad’s challenging voice crescendoed.

My fist curled shut.

“You never take enough shot, how are you supposed to score if you only take three shot? . . .” He  continued slandering me, and I knew that nothing that he said was going to be productive, so I tried to drown his voice out by focusing on counting the cars that we passed by.

1 . . . 2, 3 . . 4 . . . . . 5, 6, 7, 8, . .

As I juggled my count in my head, my focus was shattered by my dad’s continually rising voice: “Next time if you don’t take more than ten shot, then I beat you for sure.”

Aimee flinched. A few months ago, I might’ve flinched too, but I’d grown so accustomed to hearing his threats that I went right back to counting cars. Aimee sat stiffly next to me, not responding to any of this except for little, almost imperceptible sniffles that she tried to hide. She knew that it was only a matter of time before dad came at her instead. So even before he was through with me, she was already wiping snot on her jersey in anticipation of her upcoming punishment. She glared at our dad through bloodshot eyes, a defense mechanism that I recognized all too clearly. It was an attempt to free her from the helplessness we felt, an attempt to wrestle back shreds of our dignity. I yearned to diffuse the tension in the car, but flashbacks to escalated voices and physical anger warn me against wasting my breath.

&nbsp;

Aimee and I dread the car ride home from basketball games. It’s long been associated with us cowering from our father as he screams at us for hours for not making enough points. His disappointment and anger is never supplemented with any real feedback on how to do so though, so all I heard was that maybe I wasn’t trying hard enough, because, according to our dad, if I really wanted to, I should’ve been able to score more.

As much as I knew that the mere will to score doesn’t translate to the ability to do so, I also knew that failure to perform to the standards set for me would result in a barrage of angry attacks and threats. During games, instead of focusing on the next play, I became bogged down by moments when I messed up or when I missed shots. My dad’s demands to “make your layups!” as if I was deliberately trying to miss them or something, constantly echoed in the back of my mind. His words jostled out the productive voices of my coaches, my teammates, and myself. My fear of him led me to play timidly and passively.

There were a few moments throughout elementary and middle school that I believed that my dad was right, and that I just didn’t want to score enough. As much as I tried to ice out his criticism, as much as I slowly built up walls to protect myself from my dad’s scalding comments, his attitude consumed me. My self-esteem became inextricably intertwined with success and achievement. Failure to score enough points wasn’t met by feedback and encouragement to do better next time, but by loathing and punishment. The do-or-die incentive that my dad posed caused the prospect of failure to terrify me. It caused my failures to define me, and in order to avoid failure, I developed risk-aversion and low self-esteem that continued to plague me throughout my high school years.

9 . . . 10, 11 . . . . . 12 . . . the cars outside were starting to swerve and blur—a combination of my dad’s angry swerving and the frustrated tears brimming up at the bottom of my eyes that I desperately tried to blink away.

<hr />

&nbsp;

My heart started to pound before I even walked into the classroom. Madison, my friend I walk to first period with every day, turns the doorknob and opens the heavy wooden door, exposing the imposing, bleak interior of room 251. The seats are arranged in a big circle so that everyone can easily stare at you when you talk. The front of the classroom is where the dusty chalkboard with the discussion question of the day sits. There are two seats in front of it. One for the teacher, and to the left, the assigned seat which I awkwardly plop down into. My face heats up immediately as I become hyper aware of how everyone will be staring at the board above my head.

“Morning, everyone,” my teacher introduces, while her hand glides punctually over the board, “I hope you enjoyed the reading last night. Today we will be discussing the question of whether or not people should change themselves to make other people more comfortable around them.

“Remember,” she says after a pause, “everyone will be participating today.”

I look up from the wooden table, upon which I’ve already left an angry, sweaty imprint of my burning hands. I turn to look at the question scribbled on the worn out, green board. The harsh yellow writing burns in my mind. I frantically search for any possible arguments.

“Spencer, start us off,” I hear from my right.

“I think in this example, a black man should not have to whistle constantly while walking down the sidewalk. Although it may make him look a little less imposing, the fact that, uh, others stereotype him is not his problem, rather, it is up to them to confront their biases.”

“I agree,” Patrick chips in, “It isn’t just to expect him to change because of what others think about him. There is nothing about him besides the stereotypes associated with his race and statute that make others afraid of him.”

Spencer and Patrick sit in the same side of the room and they never hesitate to offer their opinions. I’ve always wished I had their boldness and confidence to take over any conversation, but I can never dismiss the thought of what my classmates will think of what I have to say, and this muddles my thoughts about the topic at hand. I grasp at the strings floating around in my mind, furrowing my brows as I struggle to form a coherent thought. I have a few ideas, but I should probably form an exact script and run through it four times in my head before I raise my hand.

“On the contrary, I think sometimes there are serious situations in which doing something to try to alleviate other people’s anxieties may actually be warranted,” counters Keyler, the boy sitting across from me, “as much as it sucks, imagine a girl walking down an alley alone at night, and a guy is walking towards her. The reality of our society is that the girl has a right to be afraid, and in that situation it may make sense for the guy to feel obligated to give her space, or do something else to make himself appear less threatening.”

It’s a good point, I’ll admit, and I could add on, but if I open up my mouth, nonsense would spew out of my shaking lungs, and I’ll say something dumb. I hold off on raising my hand, until, one by one, my teacher has checked off everyone else’s name on her wooden clipboard.

In the last three minutes of class, my teacher looks at me, her usual bored and stoic face is plastered with an expression of pity.

“Tinah,” she says, “you’re the only one who hasn’t talked, what do you think?”

Everyone’s head swivels and fixates on me. The room begins to tilt and lurch. My dry mouth opens, closes. I feel like a fish out of water, I can barely breathe, and my only thought is how my heart is pounding so hard that it’s probably audible to the person next to me.

I clear my throat, hesitate, until unscripted words tumble out.

“I think, uh, I think it wouldn’t be fair to expect people to, uh, . . . gionwlkg . . . owk . . .”

&nbsp;

It’s over. I sink down into my chair as the bell rings. I survived, and although I had spoken with a nice, unintended vibrato, I didn’t pass out like I thought I would. Still, to this day, I can’t recall a single coherent thought that I said.

Despite my friends in that class telling me that no one was actually paying attention to the discussion, I believed that anything I said would be used for others to judge and put me down. Because for me, the high expectations that have always been placed on me, as well as my father’s reprimanding voice always surfacing from the back of my mind, incites within me the urge to cower instead of stand and fight in times of performance. The world was never a supportive place that I could trust, but instead, everyone was cold, calculating, and unforgiving—any mistake that I made would be permanently ingrained in the memories of others, because it for sure haunted my dad’s and mine. My fear of judgement constrained me to the point where I developed physical symptoms of anxiety that plagued me in my sophomore year of english class. Speaking up opened up windows for others to see my brain’s thought process, and I cursed my body for literally shaking out of fear of this vulnerability.

Like the people who can command a classroom and not be afraid to be the loudest voice, there are also the ball hogs who can step into a gym and not care at all what the other people in the gym think about them. I was never one of those people.

That fact was made abundantly clear that summer. My family and I had driven all the way down to my hometown in Minnesota, and after a night spent tightening the pillows I had placed over my head to try blocking out the train-like roar of my dad’s loud snoring until 4 AM, I was sluggishly running up the familiar court of Jefferson High School at the tipoff of our 8 AM game.

A few plays into the game, the shrill shriek of the ref’s whistle pierced my ears. Our team jogged to the bench to gather in a huddle. As I jostled through the throng of players, I emerged to the front of the huddle, where I saw my coach’s finger directly pointed an inch away from my face.

“You,” Stan said, “stop passing up shots and shoot the damn ball, you were open that last play.”

My eyebrows raised. I knew which play he was talking about, and while I suppose I was a little open, I hadn’t thought that the three would’ve been the best shot for the team.

“Or just drive the ball,” he continued, “you’re one of the best players on the team, stop giving the ball up or I’ll sit you out.”

The ref blew his whistle again. As we left the huddle, I felt two thumps on my back. I turned.

“Hey, you got it,” Jenna said.

I nodded and smiled at her, before taking the court again.

We run up and down the court again for the last few minutes until the end of the half, and I made sure to take one more open shot like Stan had told me to do. As the last twelve seconds of the half counted down, I had the ball again at the top of the key.

“Take her!” Stan shouts from the opposite side of the court.

With my first step, I boldly challenged my defender, blowing right past her. With the basket in sight, I prepared to take the final shot. But I hesitated, looking wildly helpless. It was then when the familiar voices invaded my head, consuming me with doubt that overrode my instinct to score. I stopped and threw the ball away to my teammate, Claire, who was forced to throw up a contested shot. As the last second ticked away, her shot smacked off the backboard as hard as my coach smacked his head.

Running in to the huddle at halftime, I could already tell from Stan’s deadset face that he was not happy.

“Ok Tinah, what’d I just tell you? I know you heard me telling you to ‘take her,’ but you passed the ball. You threw the ball away again! And look what kinda shot we got. I can’t play you if you’re gonna keep playing like this. So the starters are starting the second half, except Jenna, you take Tinah’s spot.”

As the new starters took the court, I was too shocked to even cry. I turned to join the bench, and I heard my teammates apologizing, trying to console me, or saying that Stan was being dumb, but I quietly looked onwards, walking doggedly to the end of the bench.

&nbsp;

“We lost because Stan didn’t put you in,” Mr. Khan said.

“If only he wasn’t so stubborn,” Ms. Murray echoed.

I didn’t really know what to say. I hadn’t yet decided whether or not what Stan did was justified. All I knew was that I was shocked and frustrated at having had to keep the bench warm for a whole half. I opened my mouth to reply to my teammates’ parents, but I quickly shut it again when I saw Stan beckoning from behind them.

It was hard to hear, especially after we lost, but Stan had good intentions for benching me.

“I’ve been coaching you for three years now, and I’ve seen how good you are. But that right there was embarrassing. You play like you aren’t one of the best players on the court.”

“But, but I’m uh, I’m not one of, uh . . .”

Stan shakes his head incredulously, his eyes narrowing, “you dominate in practice. But you don’t show out in games. You’re might as well just sit on the bench if you’re gonna play passively, because you aren’t contributing like I know you can. All you do is, like, run up and down the fucking court.”

“But I don’t usually take contested shots-”

“You take them in practice and you always knock ‘em down. How will you ever know if you can make them in games if you never try?” Stan was beginning to talk more and more heatedly, his words were accompanied by rapid gesticulation.

“But-”

“Don’t but me,” he scoffs with a chilly laugh, “you have no excuses to make. All I want is for you to play like I know you can. I want you to have a demanding presence. Every time you step on the court, you should be the loudest one in the gym — the player that every opponent and coach knows and worries about. I know you can do that.”

I shut my mouth then, and stood stiffly in place, nodding earnestly as he continued to lecture.

Stan’s dose of tough love made me realize that it wasn’t selflessness that made me pass the ball to Claire, but fear. I feared how I would look if I missed a shot; I feared how my classmates would react if I said something dumb; I feared what others would think if I stepped out of my comfort zone. By never facing my fear of vulnerability and failure, I would never reach my fullest potential. I realized that he really was trying to do what was best for me when he benched me.

“Thank you,” I say as he turns to leave.

<hr />

&nbsp;

John sits hunched over on the curb next to me, shaking, his head cradled in his hands.

“Are you cold?” I ask, wrapping my coat around him.

“No, I just can’t . . . can’t stop shaking,” he musters through his sniffles.

My best friend’s energetic and intense demeanor that I’ve grown to love is gone, replaced with the trembling figure breaking down next to me.

“It’s gonna be okay,” I whisper, trying to convince both of us.

“I’m just going through a tough time, and n-none of my guy friends try to understand,”

“Well, I’m always here for you.”

“That’s why I always ask you how you’re doing, ‘cause I wanna know that you’re okay.”

“I already told you, I’m fine.”

“Fine doesn’t mean anything though” he protests between quick shallow breaths, “that’s just a cop-out.”

“But like, I literally don’t feel anything, it’s just an average day,” I insist.

“Tinah, I don’t think you’re just fine, I think you’re afraid of finding out how you really feel.”

The headlights of his ride finally find us. John gets up, wipes away his tears, and leaves me alone with the unforgiving moon, his final words swirling through my mind.

&nbsp;

Later, I tried to gauge how I really felt. Every day after school, I had a basketball practice or game, and when that ended I went straight to another person’s house to tutor. Then I would eat, shower, start homework, write essays if I had time, and prepare for the next day. I kept myself busy every second and I was so focused on my work that I didn’t even have time to dwell on how much I had to do, or how much it was stressing me out.

But something else I didn’t make time to do was check up on my best friend. Because while I was hiding my emotions, John was feeling his fully, and I failed to realize that. Even while he was crying, shaking, and curled up on the curb, he was stronger than I was. He showed strength by confronting his pain straight on and by being completely vulnerable and human in his weakness.

Sometime along the many years of angry car rides, I’ve learned how to tame my emotions and harness my tears. Instead of being vulnerable and real with my raw emotions, I conditioned myself to believe that despite anything I may be feeling at a specific moment, everything would eventually work out. This sentiment has allowed me to almost transcend my worries and doubts. But I hadn’t realized that it had gotten to a point where instead of healthily being in tune with my thoughts and emotions, and then transcending them, I was blatantly ignoring them and pretending that they weren’t there. I numbed myself to stress and anxiety as an unhealthy way to cope with these negative emotions, but in doing so, I also became numb to my joy and happiness. I was robbing myself of experiencing the full range of human emotions. In my efforts to not feel anything, I risk being dangerously complacent and out of sync with who I am.

The purpose of feeling is to provoke change or provide positive feedback. By feeling stressed about being busy, I allow myself to settle down and reprioritize. By not repressing my dad’s rebuking reprimands to the back of my mind, and instead feeling gross and indignant at the way that my dad treats my sister and I, I gain the strength to confront him. By feeling angry and frustrated when I get benched for a half, I am inspired to redirect that into playing assertively. By feeling empathy and sadness for John on the night that he broke down, I reflect and change so that I can free myself to fully feel all of these raw emotions again.

&nbsp;]]></content:encoded>
  <excerpt:encoded><![CDATA[]]></excerpt:encoded>
  <wp:post_id>127</wp:post_id>
  <wp:post_date>2020-01-31 22:53:54</wp:post_date>
  <wp:post_date_gmt>2020-01-31 22:53:54</wp:post_date_gmt>
  <wp:post_modified>2020-01-31 23:04:58</wp:post_modified>
  <wp:post_modified_gmt>2020-01-31 23:04:58</wp:post_modified_gmt>
  <wp:comment_status>open</wp:comment_status>
  <wp:ping_status>open</wp:ping_status>
  <wp:post_name>growth-and-first-gen-mindset-a-mini-memoir</wp:post_name>
  <wp:status>publish</wp:status>
  <wp:post_parent>0</wp:post_parent>
  <wp:menu_order>0</wp:menu_order>
  <wp:post_type>post</wp:post_type>
  <wp:post_password/>
  <wp:is_sticky>0</wp:is_sticky>
  <category domain="category" nicename="uncategorized"><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_published</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>timeline_notification</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1580511237]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_rest_api_client_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[-1]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:postmeta>
    <wp:meta_key>_publicize_job_id</wp:meta_key>
    <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[40178626214]]></wp:meta_value>
  </wp:postmeta>
  <wp:comment>
    <wp:comment_id>27</wp:comment_id>
    <wp:comment_author><![CDATA[marissasun]]></wp:comment_author>
    <wp:comment_author_email>sunmarissa15@gmail.com</wp:comment_author_email>
    <wp:comment_author_url/>
    <wp:comment_author_IP>73.211.134.51</wp:comment_author_IP>
    <wp:comment_date>2020-02-01 04:40:48</wp:comment_date>
    <wp:comment_date_gmt>2020-02-01 04:40:48</wp:comment_date_gmt>
    <wp:comment_content><![CDATA[Super glad I got to read this and learn more about who you are and your background. Thanks for being so vulnerable.]]></wp:comment_content>
    <wp:comment_approved>1</wp:comment_approved>
    <wp:comment_type/>
    <wp:comment_parent>0</wp:comment_parent>
    <wp:comment_user_id>177910526</wp:comment_user_id>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>email_notification_notqueued</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1580532051]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>jabber_published</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[1580532049]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_result</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[false]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
    <wp:commentmeta>
      <wp:meta_key>akismet_history</wp:meta_key>
      <wp:meta_value><![CDATA[a:3:{s:4:"time";d:1580532049.935121;s:5:"event";s:9:"check-ham";s:4:"user";s:10:"marissasun";}]]></wp:meta_value>
    </wp:commentmeta>
  </wp:comment>
</item>

  </channel>
</rss>
